<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[future zooming]]></title>
  <link href="http://futurezoom.in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://futurezoom.in/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-15T09:42:01+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://futurezoom.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Konstantin Rubinov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The last Word]]></title>
    <link href="http://futurezoom.in/the-last-word"/>
    <updated>2014-05-10T09:28:10+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://futurezoom.in/the-last-word</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>John Gruber with the help of Aaron Shwarz relieved the pain of writing awkward
html to writing straightforward
<a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>.  Yes, yes, yes and
yes! Was it difficult? &ndash; I cannot know.  Was it needed? &ndash; Yes!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>From:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">&quot;entry-content&quot;</span><span class="nt">&gt;&lt;p&gt;</span>John Gruber with the help of Aaron Shwarz
</span><span class='line'>relieved the pain of writing awkward html to writing straightforward
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;a</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot;</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Markdown<span class="nt">&lt;/a&gt;</span>.
</span><span class='line'>Yes, yes, yes and yes! Was it difficult? <span class="ni">&amp;ndash;</span> I cannot know.
</span><span class='line'>Was it needed? <span class="ni">&amp;ndash;</span> Yes!<span class="nt">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>we&rsquo;ve got:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'>John Gruber with the help of Aaron Shwarz relieved the pain of writing awkward
</span><span class='line'>html to writing straightforward
</span><span class='line'>[Markdown](http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/).  Yes, yes, yes and
</span><span class='line'>yes! Was it difficult? - I cannot know.  Was it needed? - Yes!
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>In the following I will argue that <strong>before long <em>Markdown</em> will kill <em>Word</em></strong>.  I
am talking about you, <em>MS Word</em>. Believe me: <em>Markdown</em> with all its
seemingly superficial simplicity has the power to throw such an unforgivable
blow.</p>

<h2>Prelude</h2>

<p>We seemed to have been stuck with <em>Word</em> forever.</p>

<p>Except for things do not stay in one place. In the last decade a number of
species of text manipulation and formatting tools have become dramatically
better and fitter, though working with plain text (code) for computer programs.
<em>Word</em> seems to remain much the same and we seem to have become resigned to its
interface and behavior.</p>

<p>When I say dramatically better, I am looking into the direction of the modern
text and code editors and IDEs, tools that software developers and designers
use. Just look at <em>Sublime Text</em> and catching up <em>Atom</em> or <em>Coda2</em> &mdash; sleek,
extensible, fast.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>  <em>Sublime Text</em>, for instance, has taken the best of what
is out there in code manipulation and put it into an appealing interface. Any
software developer or web designer who cares about her tools has a well-tuned
IDE or editor of choice.</p>

<p>Other alternatives to <em>Word</em> have been around since early Cenozoic times:
powerful text editors like <em>Vim</em> or <em>Emacs</em> are around for decades.  Whereas
<em>LaTeX</em> &mdash; a typesetting system for formatting sophisticated articles &mdash; is
extensively used in scientific community since 1980s.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<h2>The Effort</h2>

<p>After working with <em>Markdown</em> documents for long enough, I
realized that Markdown-style text editing is a great middle point between
WYSYWIG and markup-based text processing. (I am aware of pro and contra
decoupling text manipulation from styling.)  However, only now <strong>the effort of
working with markup-based solution is less than an effort of editing in WYSYWIG
mode</strong>.  To me, this is a new spiral in a slow evolution of text manipulation
&mdash; a tipping point for adoption of Markdown-style text editing by general
users.</p>

<p>And it&rsquo;s already there.  <em>Markdown</em> kinds spread over the Web and are now
almost everywhere: Wikipedia, StackOverflow, Github, blogs (including this one)
to name a few. New stylish editors for Markdown appear:
<a href="http://mouapp.com">Mou</a>, <a href="http://ulyssesapp.com">Ulysses III</a>.</p>

<p>Why? Because <em>Markdown</em> is simple and adequate. You can type it in a <em>Notepad</em>
or on your phone and get a result of a <em>Word</em> value.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<h2>Separation of concerns: Content, Structure and Style</h2>

<!-- This one is not new. No one needs to invent a wheel here. -->


<p><em>Markdown</em> allows you to focus on Content and Structure, and only on them.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>
Then you focus on Style, independently. Style is external to the content and it
can be flexibly adjusted.  Have you even written a postcard? Didn&rsquo;t you try out
wording on a scratch paper first?</p>

<p>There is still something we need to work on: <strong>How do we add style?</strong></p>

<p>Of course style can be in <em>CSS</em> &mdash; that is how we have it in the Internet &mdash;<br/>
<code>Markdown -&gt; HTML</code> + <code>CSS</code> = <code>Happy</code>.  Except for <em>CSS</em> is not convenient to
learn or use by general users. There must be some visual editor that would help
them to tweak and adjust styling in a intuitive way. Ideally, tweaking should
humbly live in the <em>Markdown</em> editor and spit out <em>SASS</em> or <em>CSS</em> if asked.</p>

<p>Visual <em>CSS</em> editors start to appear. For instance,
<a href="http://www.skybound.ca">Stylizer</a> is tuned for intuitive style editing with
immediate feedback, though still not an option for anyone who does not know
<em>CSS</em>.</p>

<p><a href="http://decksetapp.com">Deckset</a> approaches <em>Markdown</em> styling from another
angle &mdash; it takes care of the style and generates styled presentations. You
focus on the content and the app provides you with predefined trendy styles
(that you can&rsquo;t change, yet).</p>

<p>The solutions are out there to be put together. We don&rsquo;t need <em>Word</em> anymore. We
are changing the way we think about text editing.</p>

<p><strong>P.S.: Now that <em>Word</em> is sorted out, how do we go about <em>Excel</em>?</strong></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://www.sublimetext.com">Sublime Text</a> and <a href="http://panic.com/coda/">Coda2</a> are not free, <a href="https://atom.io">Atom by Github</a> is<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Forgot to mention &mdash; these beasts are free. <a href="http://tug.ctan.org/tex-archive/macros/latex/contrib/elsarticle/doc/els2.pdf">Here&rsquo;s one example of what <em>LaTeX</em> can produce</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>More details about <em>Markdown</em> and tools for OSX on <a href="http://computers.tutsplus.com/tutorials/introducing-markdown-on-os-x--cms-20764">Tuts+</a><a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>You can separate them in <em>Word</em> as well, but only in the first edit. Once you&rsquo;ve formatted your text in Word, all consecutive edits will require adjustment of Content, Structure and Style altogether.<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Run vertically]]></title>
    <link href="http://futurezoom.in/run-vertically"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T16:40:02+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://futurezoom.in/run-vertically</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;Don&#8217;t run vertically, run
forward!&#8221;'> I&rsquo;m no runner myself, however once I received an essential
lesson about running.  My cousin Alex told me &ndash; &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t run vertically, run
forward!&rdquo; </span></p>

<p>&mdash; &ldquo;What do you mean <em>forward</em>? How else can one run? Don&rsquo;t I run forward
already?&#8221;<br/>
In the next two minutes with very little effort I could perceive what he meant.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&mdash; &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t just push upward. Focus on getting further forward with every push.&#8221;<br/>
This was very easy to try. And it felt sooo different! I could feel the air
moving against my face and shoulders even though I was jogging! This felt
very different and new.</p>

<p>There is one difficulty to this technique. It has to be remembered. If you&rsquo;re
a dilettante runner like myself, then by default you don&rsquo;t think about this
&lsquo;trick&rsquo; and consequently you don&rsquo;t use it. It requires continuous mental effort
to remember that you need to keep pushing forward. If not &ndash; you just forget doing that.</p>

<p>I believe that the same principle applies to my daily work: each action can
push me and those with me forward in a perceivable movement. And the same
difficulty applies too: if I don&rsquo;t think actively about pushing forward, then I
may work without moving anywhere, jump on the same place, googling some useful
<strong>stuff</strong>, for instance.</p>

<p>I am convinced that with enough exercise &ldquo;pushing forward&rdquo; becomes a mental
habit. Needless to say, some work is needed.</p>

<p>P.S.: Try pushing forward when walking, it works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look for yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://futurezoom.in/look-for-yourself"/>
    <updated>2014-03-17T21:38:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://futurezoom.in/look-for-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Taking care of yourself is difficult, especially in the present. If you feel
good, you don&rsquo;t want to do anything to yourself. If you feel bad &mdash; you don&rsquo;t
want to do anything either. No responsibility required.</p>

<p>What one can do, though, is to take care of her <em>future self</em>.  This is easier,
but you must care for what your &ldquo;future you&rdquo; will become.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Try to see your &ldquo;future you&rdquo;. It may start as simple as by noticing old people
around you.  With little imagination you understand that if you&rsquo;re lucky,
you&rsquo;ll get old.  And there are consequences to it.</p>

<p>You notice, for instance, old people rubbing their knees before standing up.
With years knees get more load as leg muscles weaken.  At some point knees
start to complain.  They hurt, they get damaged, they give up.</p>

<p>You put this picture in your head and you ask yourself &mdash; what can I do to
postpone this? What can I do <em>today</em>?</p>

<p>And you know the answer. Every day, on every occasion you have, you will look
for an opportunity. Unconsciously. You will look for an opportunity to give your legs some exercise.</p>

<p>Now you take stairs, you look for opportunities to walk. This has become your
responsibility to yourself. You are taking care.</p>

<p>What is the next selfish step? You may look for other &ldquo;future things&rdquo; or
&ldquo;future people&rdquo; you care about. What can you do <em>today</em> to take care of them,
of your future?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
