<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: future | b-blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/categories/future/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-30T17:51:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Konstantin Rubinov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Run vertically]]></title>
    <link href="http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/run-vertically"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T16:40:02+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/run-vertically</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>&mdash; &ldquo;What do you mean <em>forward</em>? How else can one run? Don&rsquo;t I run forward
already?"<br/>
In the next two minutes with very little effort I could perceive what he meant.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&mdash; &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t just push upward. Focus on getting further forward with every push."<br/>
This was very easy to try. And it felt sooo different! I could feel the air
moving against my face and shoulders even though I was jogging! This felt
very different and new.</p>

<p>There is one difficulty to this technique. It has to be remembered. If you&rsquo;re
a dilettante runner like myself, then by default you don&rsquo;t think about this
&lsquo;trick&rsquo; and consequently you don&rsquo;t use it. It requires continuous mental effort
to remember that you need to keep pushing forward. If not &ndash; you just forget doing that.</p>

<p>I believe that the same principle applies to my daily work: each action can
push me and those with me forward in a perceivable movement. And the same
difficulty applies too: if I don&rsquo;t think actively about pushing forward, then I
may work without moving anywhere, jump on the same place, googling some useful
<strong>stuff</strong>, for instance.</p>

<p>I am convinced that with enough exercise &ldquo;pushing forward&rdquo; becomes a mental
habit. Needless to say, some work is needed.</p>

<p>P.S.: Try pushing forward when walking, it works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look for yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/look-for-yourself"/>
    <updated>2014-03-17T21:38:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rubinovk.github.io/b-blog/look-for-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Taking care of yourself is difficult, especially in the present. If you feel
good, you don&rsquo;t want to do anything to yourself. If you feel bad &mdash; you don&rsquo;t
want to do anything either. No responsibility required.</p>

<p>What one can do, though, is to take care of her <em>future self</em>.  This is easier,
but you must care for what your &ldquo;future you&rdquo; will become.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Try to see your &ldquo;future you&rdquo;. It may start as simple as by noticing old people
around you.  With little imagination you understand that if you&rsquo;re lucky,
you&rsquo;ll get old.  And there are consequences to it.</p>

<p>You notice, for instance, old people rubbing their knees before standing up.
With years knees get more load as leg muscles weaken.  At some point knees
start to complain.  They hurt, they get damaged, they give up.</p>

<p>You put this picture in your head and you ask yourself &mdash; what can I do to
postpone this? What can I do <em>today</em>?</p>

<p>And you know the answer. Every day, on every occasion you have, you will look
for an opportunity. Unconsciously. You will look for an opportunity to give your legs some exercise.</p>

<p>Now you take stairs, you look for opportunities to walk. This has become your
responsibility to yourself. You are taking care.</p>

<p>What is the next selfish step? You may look for other &ldquo;future things&rdquo; or
&ldquo;future people&rdquo; you care about. What can you do <em>today</em> to take care of them,
of your future?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
